Gayle King: Have a seat, Serena Williams,
غايل كينغ: تفضلي بالجلوس، سيرينا ويليامز،
or should we say, have a seat, mom.
أم علينا القول، تفضلي بالجلوس، أيتها الأم.
(Cheers)
(تصفيق)
So no doubt, you guys are like me.
بلا شك، أنّكم يا رفاق مثلي.
You saw the release of Serena
قد رأيتم سيرينا
in that great yellow bathing suit last week
في ثوب السباحة الأصفر الرائع الأسبوع الفائت
and when I saw it, all I could think of was,
وعندما رأيت ذلك، كل ما كنت أفكر به كان،
"Gosh, why couldn't she have waited til we sat onstage for TED?"
"يا إلهي، ألم تستطع الانتظار حتى نجلس على مسرح لأجل TED؟"
I was very selfish, I know.
لقد كنت أنانية جداً، أعلم.
So I asked you about that picture,
لذا سألتك عن تلك الصورة،
and you said nobody was supposed to see that picture.
وأخبرتني أنّه ليس من المفترض لأحدٍ أن يرى تلك الصورة.
What do you mean?
ماذا تعنين؟
Serena Williams: Well, actually, it was an accident.
سيرينا ويليامز: حسناً، في الحقيقة، لقد كان الأمر صدفة.
I was on vacation, just taking some time for myself,
لقد كنت في عطلة، أحصل على بعض الوقت لنفسي،
and I have this thing where I've been checking my status
وكنت أراجع حالتي خلال ذلك
and taking pictures every week to see how far along I'm going --
وألتقط الصور كل أسبوع لأرى كم أحرزت من تقدم --
GK: And sharing it with friends, maybe?
غايل: وتشاركينها مع أصدقائك، ربما؟
SW: No, actually I have just been saving it,
سيرينا: لا، في الحقيقة كنت أحفظ الصور فقط،
and I didn't really tell a lot of people,
ولم أخبر الكثير من الناس،
to be quite honest,
لأكون صريحة،
and I'd been saving it,
كنت أقوم بحفظ الصورة،
and you know how social media is, you press the wrong button and --
وتعلمين وسائل التواصل الاجتماعيّ تضغطين الزر الخطأ و--
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
GK: And there it was.
غايل: وهكذا انتشرت.
SW: So 30 minutes later -- my phone doesn't ring that much --
سيرينا: فبعد 30 دقيقة -- لم يكن هاتفي يرن كثيراً قبلها--
and 30 minutes later, I missed like four calls,
وبعد 30 دقيقة، تلقّيت 4 مكالماتٍ فائتة،
and I'm like, that's weird,
وقلت لنفسي هذا غريب،
and then I picked it up and I was like, oh no.
ثم قمت بالتقاط هاتفي وقلت أوه لا!
But it was a good moment.
لكنّها كانت لحظة جيدة.
I was gonna wait literally just five or six more days -- that's OK.
كنت سأنتظر حرفيّاً خمس أو ست أيام بعدها -- لا مشكلة.
GK: I know, because it was weird, Serena, because it only said 20 weeks,
غايل: أعلم، لأن الأمر كان غريباً، سيرينا، لأنه قال 20 أسبوع فقط،
so it's not like there was a whole lot of information on it.
لذا لم يبدو أنّه هنالك الكثير من المعلومات حول هذا الموضوع.
SW: Exactly, so that's what I've been doing all this time.
سيرينا: بالضبط، حسناً، هذا ما كنت أقوم به طوال ذلك الوقت.
I've been just tracking it.
كنت أتتبّع الأمر.
18, 19 -- every week I'd just take a picture and save it,
18، 19 -- كل أسبوع وكنت ألتقط صورة وأحفظها،
and I've been so good about it,
وكنت أجيد هذا الأمر،
and this was the one time that I slipped.
وكانت تلك المرة الوحيدة التي غفلت فيها عن الأمر.
GK: There you go. Well, congratulations.
غايل: ها أنت ذا. حسناً، مبارك.
SW: Yes, thank you.
سيرينا: نعم، شكراً لك.
GK: It really is OK. When you heard the news,
غايل: حقاً هذا جيدٌ حين سمعت الأخبار
were you excited? Were you afraid? Were you worried?
هل كنت متحمّسة؟ أم خائفة؟ أم قلقة؟
That you were pregnant, I mean.
أنّك كنت حامل، أعني.
SW: So I heard it two days before the beginning of the Australian Open,
سيرينا: سمعت بالأمر قبل يومين من بدء بطولة أستراليا المفتوحة للتنس،
which is one of the biggest grand slams.
والتي تعد واحدة من أكبر البطولات
GK: You found out two days before?
غايل: اكتشفت ذلك قبل يومين؟
SW: Yeah, so it was two days before, and I knew.
سيرينا: نعم، اكتشفت الأمر قبل يومين.
I was nervous.
كنت متوترة.
I wasn't quite sure what to think,
لم أكن متأكدة بمَ عليّ التفكير،
but I just knew that at that moment
ولكنني علمت في تلك اللحظة
it was really important for me to just focus right there
أنّه من المهم بالنسبة لي أن أركّز هناك
at the Australian Open,
في بطولة أستراليا المفتوحة
and I was definitely not sure what to do.
ولم أكن قطعاً متأكدةً ماذا عليّ أن أفعل.
I was like, can I play?
كنت أفكر، هل يمكنني اللعب؟
I know it's very dangerous, maybe, sometimes in the first 12 weeks or so,
أعلم أن الأمر خطرٍ جداً، ربما، خاصة في الأسابيع الـ 12 الأولى أو نحو ذلك،
so I had a lot of questions.
لذا كان في ذهني الكثير من الأسئلة.
GK: But not only did you play, Ms. Williams, you won.
غايل: لكنّك لم تقومي باللعب فقط، سيدة ويليامز، بل وفزتي كذلك.
(Cheers)
(هتاف)
SW: Yeah.
سيرينا: نعم.
May I just say, 23 grand slams to you.
بإمكاني أن أقول هنئًيا لك الفوز بـ 23 لقابًا من ألقاب الجراند سلام.
SW: Thank you.
سيرينا: شكراً لكِ.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
GK: While pregnant!
غايل: بينما أنتِ حامل!
SW: Well, I was looking for another handicap, so ... no.
سيرينا: حسناً، لقد كنت أبحث عن إعاقة أخرى، لذا .. لا.
GK: Did you play differently that game, knowing you were pregnant?
غايل: هل لعبتِ بشكلٍ مختلفٍ في تلك المباراة لأنك على علم بحملكِ؟
SW: I did. It wasn't very easy.
سيرينا: نعم، ولم يكن الأمر سهلاً.
You hear all these stories about people when they're pregnant,
لأنك تسمعين تلك القصص حول النساء اللواتي يكنّ حوامل،
they get sick and they get tired.
ويمرضن ويتعبن.
GK: Have you had morning sickness?
غايل: هل أصبتِ بالإعياء الصباحي؟
SW: No, I've been so fortunate and so I haven't.
سيرينا: لا، لقد كنت محظوظة جداً، لذا لم أصب بالإعياء.
But they get really tired and they get really stressed out,
لكنّهن يصبن بالتعب والضغط الشديدين،
and I had to really take all that energy,
وقد كان عليّ أن آخذ كل تلك الطاقة،
put it in a paper bag, so to say,
وأضعها في كيس، إن صح التعبير،
and throw it away,
وألقيها بعيداً،
because I really felt like I didn't have time
لأنني شعرت فعلاً بأنّه ليس لديّ وقت
to deal with any extra emotions, any extra anything,
للتعامل مع مشاعر إضافيّة، أو أي شيءٍ إضافيّ،
because pregnant or not, no one knew,
لأنني إن كنت حاملاً أم لا، فلا أحد كان يعرف،
and I was supposed to win that tournament
وكان من المفترض أن أفوز في تلك البطولة
as I am every tournament that I show up.
كما اعتدت أن أفعل في كل بطولة،
I am expected to win,
من المتوقع منّي أن أفوز،
and if I don't win, it's actually much bigger news.
وإذا لم أفعل فسأصبح عنواناً كبيراً في الأخبار.
GK: Yeah, when you don't win, that's a big story.
غايل: نعم، عندما لم تفوزي، يكون الأمر قصةً كبيرة.
SW: Yes, so for me, I had to really take anything negative
سيرينا: نعم، لذا بالنسبة لي، كان عليّ التخلّص من أي شيء سلبي
and any emotions that I was feeling at that point
أو أي مشاعر كنت أشعر بها في ذلك الوقت
and kind of just bottle them up
ونوعاً ما أضعها جانباً
and really figure out what the next step for me to do was.
وأكتشف حقّاً ما الخطوة التالية التي عليّ القيام بها.
GK: You have a lot of support. You have a lot of love.
غايل: ولكن هنالك الكثير ممن يدعمونك ويحبونك.
Even when I was coming here, people stopped me at the airport.
حتى عند قدومي إلى هنا، أوقفني الناس في المطار.
I was saying to the flight attendant, the pilot, "Guess where I'm going?"
كنت أقول لركّاب الرحلة، والطيّار، "احزروا إلى أين أنا ذاهبة؟"
They said, "Oh my God, we're so glad she's pregnant."
فقالوا: "يا إلهي، إننا سعيدون أنها حامل."
But then you always have these cranky Yankees.
ثم يأتيكِ دوماً غريبو الأطوار.
On the way over here, somebody was telling me about Ilie Nastase,
من ناحيةٍ أخرى، كان أحدهم يخبرني عن إيلي ناستاسي،
who said some very unkind, inappropriate, dare I say racial things.
والذي قال أشياء غير لطيفة وغير لائقة وعنصريّة جداً.
You have responded to him.
وقمتِ بالردّ عليه.
I'm not even going to dignify what he said,
لن أقول حتّى ما الذي قاله،
but you responded. Why did you respond?
لكنّك قمتِ بالردّ عليه، لماذا قمت بذلك؟
SW: Well, I think there are very inappropriate comments,
سيرينا: حسناً، أعتقد أنه هناك كثير من التعليقات غير اللائقة،
and not only that, I've been really supportive of my peers
وليس ذلك فحسب، فقد كنت داعمة لنظرائي كثيراً
and the people that I've worked with.
وللأشخاص الذين عملت معهم.
I've been a pro for almost 20 years,
لقد كنت محترفة لـ 20 عامٍ تقريباً،
and so for me, it's really important to hold women up,
لذا بالنسبة لي، من المهم جداً أن يتم رفع شأن المرأة،
and it's something that these young women,
وهناك شيءٌ حول أن هؤلاء النساء الشابّات
they'll come to the locker room, they'll want to take pictures with me,
سيأتون لغرفة تبديل الملابس، وسيرغبون بالتقاط الصور معي،
and for me, it's just like,
وبالنسبة لي، فالأمر أنني
I want to be able to be a good leader and a good example for them.
أريد أن أكون قادرة على أن أكون قائدةً جيدة ومثالاً جيداً لهم.
So not only --
لذا فالأمر ليس فقط --
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Not only did he have rude things to say about me and my peers,
ليس فقط أنه كان يقول أشياء سيئة عنّي وعن زميلاتي،
I felt it was important for us to stand up for each other
فقد شعرت أنّه كان من المهم أن ندافع عن بعضنا البعض
and to stand up for myself.
وأن أدافع عن نفسي.
And at that point it was really important for me to say,
وفي تلك اللحظة، كان من المهم جداً بالنسبة لي أن أقول،
like, I'm not afraid, I'm not going anywhere,
أنني لست خائفة، وأنني لست ذاهبة إلى أي مكان،
but this is inappropriate,
لكن هذا غير لائق،
and there's time and there's a place for everything.
وأنّه هنالك زمان ومكان لكل شيء.
And that really wasn't the time and the place.
ولم يكن ذلك الوقت والزمان المناسبين.
GK: We cut the part where you said you're not going anywhere,
غايل: لقد أزلنا الجزء الذي قلتي فيه أنك لست ذاهبة إلى أي مكان،
because you'll be 36 in September. Baby's coming, 36.
لأنك ستبلغين الـ 36 من عمرك في سبتمبر والطفل قادم.
And your coach said age is always important,
ومدرّبك قال أن العمر مهمٌ دوماً،
but in tennis it's very important,
ولكنّه في التنس شديد الأهمّية،
but he has no doubt that you're coming back.
ولكن لم يكن لديه شكّ أنك ستعودين.
Have you thought, am I coming back?
هل فكرت بالسؤال، هل سأعود؟
Will I take some time off?
هل سآخذ وقتاً للراحة؟
I know the women on the tour are saying,
أعلم أن النساء في البطولة يقولون،
"How long does it take to have a baby? Two years will she be gone?"
"كم من الوقت سيستغرق إنجاب طفل؟ هل سترحل لسنتين؟"
What are you thinking?
ما الذي تفكرين به؟
SW: Well, I'm always trying to defy the odds, you know,
سيرينا: حسناً، أنا أحاول تحدّي الصعاب،
so for me everything is really mental.
لذا بالنسبة لي كل شيءٍ عقليّ.
I definitely plan on coming back. I'm not done yet.
أنا أخطط قطعاً للعودة. لم أنتهِ من التنس بعد.
I'm really inspired by my sister.
وأنا حقّاً أستلهم من أختي.
She's a year older than me, and that's something that --
إنّها أكبر مني بعامٍ واحد، وهذا أمرٌ يجعلني أفكّر --
if she's still playing, I know I can play.
إذا كانت تستطيع اللعب فيمكنني ذلك أيضاً.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And there's so many -- Roger Federer, he's a little bit older than me
وهنالك الكثيرون -- روجر فيدرير، إنه أكبر مني بقليل
and he's still winning everything, so I'm like, I know I can do that too.
ولا يزال يفوز في جميع مبارياته. لذا أفكر، أنا أعلم أنه يمكنني ذلك أيضاً.
So that's been so inspiring to me, especially recently,
لذا، فإن هذا أمراً مُلهماً بالنسبة لي، خاصة في الآونة الأخيرة،
and I know that it's something I want to do.
وأنا أعلم أنّه أمرٌ أودّ القيام به.
And my story is definitely not over yet.
وقصّتي لم تنتهِ بالتأكيد بعد.
I was talking to my coach about it,
كنت أتحدّث مع مدرّبي حول هذا الأمر،
and we were talking about how this is just a new part of my life,
وكنا نتحدّث حول أن هذا الأمر هو جزءٌ جديد من حياتي،
and my baby's going to be in the stands
وسيكون طفلي في المدرجات
and hopefully cheering for me, not crying too much.
يهتف لي كما آمل، ولا يبكي كثيراً.
GK: No, you wrote a beautiful letter to your baby yesterday
غايل: كتبت رسالةً جميلةً لطفلك البارحة
that you said -- from the oldest mommy to the youngest one,
وقلت بها -- من أكبر الأمهات إلى صغيري،
to the oldest, to the youngest, I can't wait for you to get here.
إلى الأكبر، إلى الأصغر، لا أستطيع انتظار قدومك إلى هنا.
A lot of people feel that.
الكثير من الناس يشعرون بهذا.
I saw you about a year ago, because I think about your life, Serena.
لقد رأيتك السنة الماضية لأنني أفكر بحياتك، يا سيرينا.
You've had three life-changing things in a six-month time:
لقد مررت بثلاثة أشياء غيّرت حياتك خلال فترة ستة أشهر:
pregnant, huge win, fell in love.
حملٌ، وفوزٌ كبير، ووقعتِ في الحبّ.
And when I saw you last year,
وعندما رأيتك السنة الماضية،
I was saying, "How's your love life? Da da da."
كنت أقول، "كيف هي حياتك العاطفيّة؟ الخ"
You said, "I met a guy. He's a nerdy, kinda geeky guy.
فقلت: "لقد التقيت شاباً، وهو من النوع المهووس بالتكنولوجيا الحديثة.
You won't know who he is."
ولن تعرفي من هو."
I said, "What's his name?"
فقلت لك: "ما اسمه؟"
SW: I remember talking to you about that, yes.
سيرينا: أتذكّر أنني تحدثت معك عن هذا، صحيح.
GK: And you said, "Alexis Ohanian." I said, "I know him!" He's awesome.
غايل: فقلت: "أليكس أوهانيان" فأجبتك، "أعرفه! إنّه رائع!"
But I would never put you with a nerdy geek,
ولكنني لم أكن لأتخيّلك مع هذا النوع من الشباب
and you said, you neither.
فقلت، ولا أنا كذلك.
SW: I'm going to be honest with you, I didn't either,
سيرينا: لأكن صريحةً معك، لم أكن أتخيل الأمر كذلك،
but it's been the best thing for me.
ولكنّه أفضل ما حصل لي.
GK: The best thing why?
غايل: أفضل ما حصل، لماذا؟
Does that look like a nerdy geek?
هل يبدو كعبقري مهووس بالعلم؟
Look at the shirt.
انظري إلى هذا القميص.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
No, he's a very nice guy.
لا، إنّه شابٌ لطيفٌ جداً.
SW: You can tell he's into technology.
سيرينا: يمكن القول أنه محب للتكنولوجيا.
GK: He's a very, very nice guy.
غايل: إنّه شابٌ لطيفٌ للغاية.
I like him very much.
أنا أحبّه كثيراً.
So how did he succeed when others have failed?
إذاً، كيف نجح بينما فشل الآخرون؟
How was he the one that you knew, this is the one for me?
كيف عرفت أنه هذا هو الشخص المناسب لي؟
SW: Well, I'm not going to say that,
سيرينا: حسناً، لن أقول ذلك،
but ...
ولكن ..
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
GK: Say it, Serena, say it!
غايل: قوليه، سيرينا، قوليه!
SW: Well ...
سيرينا: حسناً ..
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Yes.
نعم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
GK: But you know what I mean.
غايل: لكن تعلمين ما أقصده.
SW: He is very loving and he's very kind, and my mom says he's very considerate,
سيرينا: إنّه محبٌّ ولطيفٌ كثيراً، وقد قالت أمّي أنه متفهم كثيراً،
and when she said that to me,
وعندما قالت ذلك لي،
I was like, you know, he really is,
كنت أفكر، هو كذلك بالفعل،
and it's the little things that really make a huge difference in life.
والأشياء الصغيرة هي التي تُحدث اختلافاً كبيراً في الحياة.
GK: Like?
غايل: مثل؟
SW: Something simple.
سيرينا: شيء بسيط.
My fashion company, we have a show every year,
في شركة الأزياء خاصتي، نُقيم عرضاً كل سنة،
so in our show last year, I was running around like crazy,
وفي عرضنا السنة الماضية، كنت أتجوّل كالمجنونة،
because I do everything for the show,
لأنني كنت أقوم بكل شيء من أجل العرض،
and everything for it,
وكلّ شيء بخصوصه،
so I was running around like crazy,
لذا كنت أتجوّل كالمجنونة،
and he, it was a simple gesture of this shirt that he had,
بينما هو، وهي لفتة بسيطة منه حول القميص الذي كان بحوزته،
and he just wanted to make sure that I had the same one,
أراد فقط أن يتأكد من حصولي على القميص نفسه،
and it was -- it's a weird story.
إنّها قصةٌ غريبة.
It was better in person, I promise.
لقد كانت أفضل بشكل شخصيّ، أؤكد لك ذلك.
GK: Was it a wonderful proposal?
غايل: هل كان عرض زواجٍ رائع؟
Or was it a Beyoncé song?
أم أنّه كأغنية بيونسيه؟
"If you like it then you ought to put a ring on it"?
"إذا كنت تحب ذلك، إذاً، عليك أن تضع خاتماً حوله"؟
Were you feeling pressure to get married?
هل كنت تشعرين بالضغط بخصوص الزواج؟
Did you know it was coming?
هل كنت تعلمين أن ذلك سيحدث؟
SW: Yeah, I actually never felt pressure to get married
سيرينا: نعم، في الحقيقة لم أشعر بالضغط تجاه الزواج
and I can't say I'm the marrying type of person.
ولا أستطيع القول أنني من النوع الذي يُفضل الزواج.
I really love my life.
أنا أحبّ حياتي حقاً.
I love my freedom.
أحبّ الحريّة.
I heard that kind of changes.
علمت بهذا النوع من التغيير.
But I love everything that I do,
ولكن أحبّ كل شيءٍ أقوم به،
and I love my career,
وأحبّ مهنتي،
and I always felt like I didn't want anything to interfere with that.
ولطالما شعرت أنني لا أريد أن يتدخل شيءٌ في هذا.
I've actually been so career-oriented
لقد كانت حياتي تتمحور حول مهنتي
and in fact, when he proposed,
وفي الحقيقة، عندما تقدّم لي،
I was almost angry.
كنت غاضبةً تقريباً.
Not almost. I was angry,
ليس تقريباً. لقد كنت غاضبة،
because it was right in the middle of my training season,
لأنّه فعل ذلك تماماً في منتصف موسم التدريب الخاص بي،
and I said, "I gotta win the Australian Open.
وقلت: "عليّ الفوز ببطولة أستراليا المفتوحة.
I can't fly to Rome."
لا يمكنني السفر إلى روما."
Because he wanted to take me to Rome,
لأنّه أراد أخذي إلى روما،
and I said, "I can't. I gotta win."
لذا قلت، "لا أستطيع، عليّ الفوز."
But that's how focused I was.
ولكن هذا ما كان تركيزي عليه.
GK: This is a girl that says, "No, I can't go to Rome." OK.
غايل: هذه الفتاة التي تقول "لا أستطيع الذهاب إلى روما" حسناً.
SW: But I was really focused on reaching my goals
سيرينا: لكنني كنت أركز تماماً على تحقيق أهدافي
and I knew at that point there was one player that I wanted to pass.
وقد علمت في ذلك الوقت أنه هنالك لاعبةٌ واحدة عليّ تجاوزها.
I wanted to pass Steffi Graf's record,
كان عليّ تجاوز رقم ستيفي غرافي القياسي،
and that really meant a lot to me,
وقد عنى ذلك الكثير لي،
and when I put my mind to something,
وعندما أضع عقلي في أمراً ما،
I really am determined to reach it
فإنني أُصمّم على الوصول إليه
no matter what.
مهما كلّفني الأمر.
GK: You know, you said that for you --
غايل: لقد قلت هذا الأمر لنفسك --
I've heard you say that winning is addictive to you.
لقد سمعتك تقولين أن الفوز مدمنٌ عليكِ.
SW: It is.
سيرينا: هو كذلك.
GK: What do you mean?
غايل: ماذا تقصدين؟
SW: I feel like winning for me is superaddictive.
سيرينا: أشعر بأن إدماني على الفوز شديد.
I feel like once you experience it,
وأشعر أنّه بمجرد أن تجربيه،
you always want to get that feeling again,
ستريدين دوماً أن تعاودي الشعور به مجدداً،
and when I won my first championship, I was only 17 years old,
وعندما فزت بطولتي الأولى كان عمري 17 عاماً فقط،
but I never forgot that feeling,
ولكنني لم أنسَ ذلك الشعور أبداً،
and I feel like every time I win one,
وأشعر أنني في كل مرة أربح بطولة،
I want to reach that feeling of your first championship.
أريد أن أشعر بشعور البطولة الأولى.
There's really no feeling in the world like that.
لا يوجد شعورٌ في العالم مثله حقّاً.
And it's like, all these years of training
وبالنسبة لي، خلال كل تلك السنوات من التدرّب،
and being a little kid and playing,
وأنني كنت طفلة صغيرة وألعب التنس،
and then winning is a wonderful experience.
ثم أفوز، لقد كانت تجربة رائعة.
So for me I've always felt like I loved that feeling,
وقد شعرت أنني أحب ذلك الشعور،
and obviously I don't like the feeling of losing. I feel like --
ومن الواضح أنني لا أحبّ شعور الخسارة. وأشعر وكأن --
GK: No, in fact, people close to you say you're a very bad loser.
غايل: لا، في الحقيقة من حولك يقولون أنك خاسرة سيئة جداً.
SW: I'm not the best loser.
سيرينا: لست أفضل الخاسرين.
GK: That you're very, very, very bad.
غايل: يقولون أنك سيئة جداً جداً جداً.
Listen, no athlete, no champion likes to lose.
اسمعي، لا يوجد رياضيّ أو بطل يحب أن يخسر.
I get that.
أتفهم ذلك.
But they say when it comes to losing, you are very, very, very bad at it.
ولكنهم يقولون عندما يتعلق الأمر بالخسارة، فإنّك سيئةٌ به جداً جداً جداً.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
SW: I'm number one at losing too, so you know, that's all I can say.
سيرينا: إنني رقم واحد في الخسارة أيضاً، لذا تعلمين، هذا كل ما أستطيع قوله.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
GK: I'm always curious about the dynamic between you and Venus,
غايل: لطالما كنت فضوليّة حول الديناميكية بينك وبين فينوس،
because everybody that knows you and has followed the story
لأن كل من يعرفك أو يتابع قصتك
knows that you two are very close,
يعرف أنكما متقاربان جداً،
and you always bring your A game in whatever you do,
وأنت دائمًا تقدمين بأفضل ما لديك في أي مما تقومين به
but I often wonder, when you're playing her,
لكنيّ أتسال غالبًا وأنت تلعبين معها
do you bring your A- game because you want to do something for her
هل تقدمين قليلاً مما لديك لأنك تريدين القيام بشيء من أجلها
or do you bring your A++ game because you want to crush her.
أم تقدمين كل ما لديك لأنك تريدين تحطميها.
Is it harder for you playing her or easier?
هل من الصعب عليك أو من السهل اللعب معها!؟
SW: Well, playing Venus is like playing myself,
سيرينا: حسنًا، لعبي مع فينوس مثل لعبي مع نفسي،
because we grew up playing each other, we grew up practicing together.
لأننا كبرنا ونحن نلعب ضد بعضنا البعض، كبرنا ونحن نتدرب معًا.
And it was something that has been difficult,
وقد كان ذلك شيئًا صعبًا؛
because she's my toughest opponent.
لأنها خصمي الأقوى.
She's tall, she's fast,
إنها طويلة وسريعة،
she hits hard like me, she serves like me.
وتسدّد بقوة مثلي، وتلعب مثلي.
It's really like playing a wall.
الأمر يشبه اللعب ضد جدار حقًا.
GK: She knows you.
غايل: إنها تعرفك.
SW: She knows where I'm hitting the ball before I hit it,
سيرينا: تعرف أين سأسدّد الكرة قبل أن أسدّدها،
so it's something that is not very easy,
ولذا هو أمر غير سهل تمامًا،
but it's really about, when I go out there,
لكنني في الحقيقة، عندما أخرج لمواجهتها،
I really have to shut down my mind and I have to say to myself,
فإنني اضطر فعلًا لإيقاف عقلي ويجب أن أقول لنفسي،
"You know what?
"أتعلمين ماذا؟
I'm just playing a great player, but today I have to be better.
أنا فقط أواجه لاعبة عظيمة، لكن يجب علي اليوم أن أكون أفضل.
I don't care who it is, if it's my sister or it's my friend,
لا يهمني من تكون، إن كانت أختي أو صديقتي،
today is the day I have to show up and I have to be better
اليوم يجب علي أن أتواجد وأن أكون أفضل،
and I have to want it more than anyone else at this moment
ويجب أن أرغب في ذلك أكثر من أي أحد في تلك اللحظة
anywhere on this world."
في أي مكان في العالم."
GK: So never on the court do you fall back for Venus?
غايل: إذن، أنت لم تتراجعي أبدًا أمام فينوس في الملعب؟
Because, you know, it was always Venus and Serena.
لأنه، كما تعلمين، لطالما كان فينوس وسيرينا سويًا.
SW: Yes.
سيرينا: أجل.
GK: And now baby sister has surpassed older sister.
غايل: والآن، تفوّقت الأخت الصغر على أختها الكبرى.
Do you feel guilt about that?
هل تشعرين بالذنب حيال ذلك؟
Do you feel joy in that?
هل تشعرين بالسعادة حياله؟
Is that a difficult position for you?
هل هذا وضع صعب بالنسبة لك؟
SW: I don't feel anything in there.
سيرينا: لا أشعر بأي شيء حيال ذلك.
In my life, it still and forever is always going to be Venus and Serena.
طوال حياتي، لا يزال وسيظل دائمًا فينوس وسيرينا سويًا.
She's really love of my life, she's my best friend,
إنها حقًا حب حياتي، وصديقتي المفضلة،
she's my soul mate.
إنها توأم روحي.
I mean --
أعني --
There's pictures of her pushing me,
هناك صور لها وهي تدفعني،
really low-quality pictures or else I would have shared them,
صور جودتها منخفضة للغاية، كنت لأنشرهم لولا ذلك،
of her pushing me in a stroller on a tennis court,
وهي تدفعني في عربة أطفال في ملعب تنس،
and she always took care of me.
وكانت دائمًا تعتني بي.
I used to spend all of my allowance money on the ice cream truck and stuff,
اعتدت انفاق مصروفي أمام عربة المثلجات وأمور كهذه،
and she would take her money and give it to me at school
كانت تأخذ مصروفها وتعطيه لي في المدرسة
and make sure I had something to eat and she would go without,
وتحرص علي أن يكون لدي ما آكله بينما تذهب بدون أكل،
and that's the kind of person she actually is
إنها من هذا النوع من الأشخاص في الحقيقة
since I've always known her.
منذ أن عرفتها.
So we always have this incredible respect for each other
لذا لدينا دائمًا هذا الاحترام الاستثنائي تجاه بعضنا البعض
and this incredible love,
وهذا الحب الاستثنائي،
and I think it's important for people to realize you can be successful
أعتقد أنه من المهم أن يدرك الناس أن بإمكانك أن تكوني ناجحة
but you can still have a wonderful relationship.
ويظل بإمكانك أن تحظي بعلاقة رائعة.
On the court we are mortal enemies,
في الملعب، نحن عدوّتين لدودتين،
but the second we shake hands, we are best friends again.
لكن بمجرد أن نتصافح، نصبح صديقتين مقرّبتين مجددًا.
And if I lose, it might be a day later for me,
وإذا خسرت، قد يكون هذا ليوم واحد بالنسبة ليّ،
but for Venus --
أما فينوس--
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
GK: There's never a time on the court where you hit the ball
غايل: ألم يكن هناك مرة وأنت في الملعب تضربين الكرة
and say, "That's for seventh grade when you did the blah blah blah"?
وتقولين "هذه من أجل الصف السابع عندما فعلت كذا وكذا"؟
You never have any moment like that?
لم تمر عليكِ لحظة كهذه؟
SW: I feel like she should have those moments,
سرينا: اعتقد أنه يجب عليها المرور بلحظات كهذه
because she's never done anything bad to me,
لأنها لم تقترف أي شيء سيء حيالي،
but I'm the youngest. I'm the younger sister.
لكن أنا الأصغر، أنا الأخت الصغرى.
GK: Serena, she's never done anything bad to you? Really?
غايل: سرينا ألم تقم بأي شيء سيء تجاهك؟ حقًا؟
I have three sisters. I can think of some stuff I've done bad.
لدي ثلاث أخوات، بأمكاني تذكر بعض الأشياء السيئة التي قمت بها.
SW: Unless she brainwashed me to forget them.
سيرينا: إلا إذا أنها قد غسلت دماغي حتى أنساها
GK: No, but the love you have for her I know is very pure. I know that.
غايل: لا، لكنه الحب الذي تحملينه في قلبك لها أعرف أنه حب خالص.
SW: Yes. GK: I know that.
سيرينا: نعم. غايل: أعرف ذلك.
SW: We were always brought up to be superclose,
سيرينا: لقد ولدنا لكي نكون مقربتين جدًا.
and we are incredibly close.
ونحن بالفعل مقربتين للغاية.
Not only her.
ليس هي فقط.
I have three other sisters as well, and we were always so close.
لدي ثلاث أخوات أيضًا، وكنا دائما مقربين جدًا.
GK: So before a big match, the two of you don't get together
غايل: هل قبل مبارة كبيرة لا تجتمعان أنتما الإثنان
and say, look, we're going to go out there and -- there's nothing?
وتقولان، يبدو، أننا سنخرج إلى هناك و-- ثم لاشيء؟
SW: Well, it's funny. Before the Australian Open,
سيرينا: هذا مضحك. قبل بطولة أستراليا المفتوحة
we were in the locker room together,
كنا في غرفة تبديل الملابس معًا،
and I always pick on her, so I pulled out my camera while she was changing.
وأنا دائمًا ما اضايقها، لذا سحبت كاميرتي عندما كانت تبدل ملابسها.
I started taking pictures of her, which is totally inappropriate,
بدأت بالتقاط الصور لها، وهو أمر غير لائق تمامًا،
but she was so mad at me.
لكنها كانت غاضبة مني جدًا.
She's like, "Serena, stop!" And I was just laughing at her.
وقالت ليّ، "سيرينا، كفى!" وكنت أضحك عليها وحسب.
But that's the kind of relationship that we have, and like I said,
تلك هي نوعية علاقتنا، وكما قلت،
the second we step on the court,
في اللحظة التي دخلنا فيها الملعب
it was like, we were definitely mortal enemies,
كان الأمر ويكأننا قطعًا عدوتين لدودتين،
but the second we stepped off, and moments before, we're just --
لكن اللحظة التي خرجنا فيها واللحظات قبلها كنا --
It is what it is, because at the end of the day,
نكون ما نحن عليه، لأنه في نهاية المطاف،
she'll always be my sister.
ستكون أختي دائمًا.
I'm not going to play Australia in --
لن ألعب في بطولة أستراليا في --
Well, who knows, I've been playing forever,
حسنًا، من يعلم، لقد كنت ألعب دائمًا،
but I don't think I'll be playing in 50 years, say?
لكن لا أعتقد أنيّ سألعب بعد 50 عامًا، مثلًا؟
Let's be safe and say 50 years.
لنكن في مأمن ونقول 50 عامًا.
GK: I don't know, Serena. There's never been anybody like you.
غايل: لا أعرف يا سيرينا. فأنت لا يشبهك أحد.
When you think about it, never been anybody
عندما تفكرين في الأمر، لم يكن هناك أحدًا
who has intersected gender and race the way you have,
قد تخطى نوع الجنس والعرق مثلك،
the dominance that you have and the scrutiny that you have.
هيمنتك وامعانك.
And when you were growing up, did you say, "I want to be like that"?
وفي أثناء نشأتك، هل قلتِ "أود أن أكون مثل ذلك؟"
Because now little girls are looking at you
لأن الآن الفتيات الصغيرات يتطلعون إليك
saying, "I want to be like that."
قائلات، " أود أن أكون مثل ذلك."
Who was the "I want to be like that" for you?
فمن هو الشخص الذي وددت أن تكوني مثله؟
SW: Well, it's interesting, and I'm glad you brought that up.
سيرينا: حسنًا، هذا أمر شيق، وأنا سعيدة كونك طرحت هذا السؤال
For me, when I grew up, I always wanted to be the best,
بالنسبة إليّ عندما كبرت، أردت دائمًا أن أكون الأفضل،
and I said, if you want to be the best, you've got to emulate the best.
وقلت لنفسي، إذا أردتِ أن تكوني الأفضل، فيجب أن تقلدي الأفضل.
So when I started to go on tour when I was really young,
لذا عندما شرعت في الذهاب في جولات عندما كنت صغيرة جدًا،
I would see Steffi Graf, I would see Monica Seles,
رأيت ستيفي غراف، و رأيت مونيكا سيليس،
and I would even see Pete Sampras,
ورأيت حتى بيت سامبراس،
and I would see what they did,
ورأيت ما فعلوه،
and I noticed that Steffi and Monica
ولاحظت أن ستيفي ومونيكا
didn't really talk to a lot of the other players,
لايتحدثن إلى كثير من اللاعبين الأخرين،
and they kind of were on their own,
وكانتا نوعًا ما مكتفين بذواتهم،
and they were just so focused
وكانتا منبهتين جدا فقط
and I would see Pete Sampras, the technique that he did,
ورأيت بيت سامبراس، وبراعته الفنية التي قام بها
and I was like, "I want to do that."
وقلت، "أود القيام بمثل هذا."
So I did that, and I felt that to be the best,
وفعلت ذلك، وشعرت أنه لتكون الأفضل،
and if you want to be the best,
وإذا أردت أن تكون الأفضل،
you have to hang around people
يجب أن تصاحب الناس
and you have to look at people that are the best,
وأن تتطلع إلى أفضل الناس،
because you're not going to be the best
لأنك لن تكون الأفضل
if you're looking at someone that's not at the top level.
إذا كنت تتطلع إلى شخص ليس من أعلى المستويات.
GK: People say nobody works as hard as you.
غايل: يقول الناس أن لا أحد يعمل بجد مثلك.
SW: I'm a very hard worker. GK: That's what I heard.
سيرينا: أنا أعمل بجد. غايل: هذا ما سمعته.
SW: People say, "Oh, she's talented, she's athletic."
سيرينا: يقول الناس، " اوه، أنها موهوبة، ورياضية."
Actually, I wasn't. I was really small for my age.
في الواقع، لم أكن. كنت صغيرة الجسم جدًا بالنسبة لسنيّ.
I grew up when I got older,
ونضجت عندما كبرت،
and I had to work really hard,
وتتطلب الأمر أن أعمل بجد أكثر،
and I think one of the reasons why I fight so hard and I work so hard
وأعتقد أن أحد أسباب قتالي وسعي بجد
is because I was really, really, really small.
هو أنيّ كنت صغيرة الجسم جدًا بحق.
GK: Yeah.
غايل: نعم
You are no longer small.
والآن أنتِ لم تعودي صغيرة الجسم.
SW: No, I'm fully grown now.
سيرينا: لا، لقد نَضجت تمامًا الآن.
But I was small when I was really young for whatever reason.
ولكنيّ كنت صغيرة الجسم عندما كنت شابة لسبب ما.
I think Venus maybe ate all the Wheaties.
أعتقد أنه ربما كانت فينوس تأكل كل حبوب الويتيز.
GK: You know, the other thing people talk about is your body.
غايل: تعلمين أن الشيء الآخر الذي يتحدث عنه االناس هو جسمك.
Your body brings men and women to their knees.
يجعل جسدك الرجال والنساء ينحنون على ركبهم.
And I mean in a good way.
أعني بطريقة حسنة.
A lot has been made about your body.
هناك الكثير جعلوا من جسدك.
It's a work of art, it's masculine, it's glorious,
أنه قطعة فنية و ذكوري وبديع،
there's never been anything like it.
ولا يوجد شبيه له.
Did you have body issues when you were growing up?
هل كانت لديك مشاكل مع جسدك وأنت تكبرين؟
Have you always been comfortable with your body?
هل كنت تشعرين بالإرتياح بخصوص جسدك؟
SW: It's interesting, because when you're a teenage female
سيرينا: هذا ممتع، لأنه كونك أنثى مراهقة
growing up in the public eye,
نشأت تحت أنظار الجمهور،
it is a lot of scrutiny that you face,
فأنك تواجهين تفحص دقيق،
and as any female that's a teenager,
وكأي أنثى مراهقة،
I definitely was not comfortable in my body.
فبالتأكيد لم أحظى بالإرتياح تجاه جسدي.
I didn't like it.
لم يعجبني.
I didn't understand why I had muscles.
لم أفهم لمَ كان لدي عضلات.
And I stopped lifting weights.
وتوقفت عن رفع الأثقال.
I was like, I'm not going to do this.
كان الأمر مثل، لن أفعل هذا.
But then after I won the US Open,
لكن بعد أن كسبت بطولة الولايات المتحدة المفتوحة
I realized that my body helped me reach goals that I wanted to reach,
أدركت حينها أن جسدي ساعدني على تحقيق الأهداف التي أردتها
and I wanted to be happy with it,
وأردت أن أكون سعيدة بذلك،
and I was so appreciative of it.
وكنت مقدّرة جدًا لذلك.
I'm always healthy.
أتمتع دائمًا بصحة جيدة.
I'm really fortunate and superblessed,
أنا محظوظة ومباركة جدًا،
and I felt like not only am I happy with my body,
وشعرت أنيّ لست فقط سعيدة بجسدي،
but I want other people and other young girls
بل أردت الناس والفتيات الشابات
that have experienced what I've experienced
الذين مروا بنفس تجربتي
to be happy with themselves.
أن يكونوا سعداء بأنفسهم
So whatever people say --
فأي مما يقوله الناس-
masculine, whatever, too much, too little --
ذكوري، أو أي ما يكون، كبير جدًا أو ضئيل جدًا --
I'm OK with it as long as I love myself.
فأنا راضية عنه لطالما أحب نفسي.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
GK: I know you learn a lot from winning,
غايل: أعلم أنك تتعلمين الكثير من الفوز،
but what have you learned from losing?
لكن ما الذي تعلمتيه من الخسارة؟
SW: I hate to lose, but I think losing has brought me here today.
سيرينا: أكره الخسارة، لكن أعتقد أنها أتت بي إلى هنا اليوم
The only reason I am who I am is because of my losses,
سبب كوني ما أنا عليه هو بفضل خسائريّ،
and some of them are extremely painful,
بعضهم كان مؤلمًا حقًا،
but I wouldn't take any of them away,
لكن لن أتخلى عن أيَّا منها،
because every time I lose,
لأن كل مرة أخسر فيها،
it takes a really long time for me to lose again
يأخذ مني الأمر وقتًا طويلًا حتى أخسر ثانية
because I learn so much from it.
لأنيّ أتعلم الكثير منها.
And I encourage everyone that I talk to --
وأشجع كل من أتحدث إليه --
I'm like, listen, if you lose or if something happens --
أسمعوا، إذا ما خسرتم أو حدث شيء ما --
not in sports -- in business or in school --
ليس في الرياضة -- بل في العمل أو المدرسة --
learn from it.
تعلموا منها.
Don't live in the past, live in the present,
لا تعيشوا في الماضي، بل عيشوا الحاضر،
and don't make the same mistakes in the future.
ولا ترتكبوا نفس الأخطاء في المستقبل.
That's something that I always try to live by.
هذا ما أحاول التعايش به.
in the Catskills or Poconos or are you going to do it in Florida?
في كاتسكيلز أو بوكونوس أو ستقيميه في فلوردا؟
What are you thinking?
ما الذي تفكرين به؟
Big or small?
كبير أو صغير؟
SW: We're thinking medium size. We don't want to do too big,
سيرينا: نفكر في زفاف متوسط الحجم. لأننا لانريده كبير جدًا
but then we're like, OK, we can't say no to this person, this person.
لكن حينها سيكون الأمر، حسنًا لا يمكننا القول لا لهذ الشخص أو لذاك.
So we're thinking medium size and we're just thinking --
فنحن نفكر في زفاف متوسط، وهو مجرد تفكير--
My personality is a lot of fun. Hopefully you can see that today.
شخصيتيّ مرحة جدًا. آمل أن تكونوا لاحظتم ذلك اليوم.
I'm not too serious.
لست صارمة جدًا.
GK: And you like to dance.
غايل: وتحبين الرقص.
And the next chapter for Serena Williams is what?
وما هو الفصل التالي في حياة سيرينا ويليمز؟
SW: Oh, next for me.
اوه، التالي في حياتي.
Obviously I'm going to have a baby
من الواضح أنيّ سأنجب طفلًا
and I'm going to stay fit and kind of come back and play tennis
وسأحافظ على لياقتي وسأعود للعب التنس
and keep working on my fashion line.
وأستمرفي العمل على خط الأزياء خاصتي.
That'll be really fun.
سيكون هذا ممتع جدّا.
GK: Do you know if it's a boy or girl?
غايل: هل تعلمين إذا ما كان صبي أم فتاة؟
SW: I don't. I have a feeling of one or the other.
لا أعلم، أشعر بأنه سيكون هذا أو ذاك.
It's a 50-50 chance, but I have a feeling.
أن الأمر متساوٍ، لكنيّ أشعر بشيء.
GK: Gayle is a unisex name.
غايل: غايل اسم يطلق على كلا الجنسين
Whatever you and Alexis decide, we are cheering you on!
فأي كان ما ستقررونه أنتِ والكسيس، فأننا نشجعكم عليه!
SW: Thank you for that. GK: You're welcome.
سيرينا: شكرًا لكِ. غايل: على الرحب والسعة
We are cheering you on, Serena Williams. SW: Thank you so much.
نحن نشجعك يا سيرينا. سيرينا: شكرّا جزيلّا لكم.
Thank you guys.
أشكركم يا رفاق.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)